<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Christian Engels&#x27; Homepage - Games</title>
    <subtitle>Homepage of Christian Engels</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://narfinger.github.io/categories/games/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://narfinger.github.io/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://narfinger.github.io/categories/games/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Brothers - In the Nick of Time</title>
        <published>2015-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2015-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/brothers-in-the-nick-of-time/"/>
        <id>https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/brothers-in-the-nick-of-time/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;narfinger.github.io&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2015&#x2F;brothers-in-the-nick-of-time&#x2F;brothers-taleoftwosons.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Brothers - A tale of two sons&quot; is a well renowned game and one of the indie darlings from 2013. I recently played through it
and can now give my assessment of this. Normally I do not care about spoiler warnings as I assume everybody does either not care
or already knows the game. Second, most spoiler warning can actually already be a spoiler. Here I might break with my tradition.
After a break there will be full spoilers, you are warned.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should also mention that the game did not quite capture me as many other people. The reasons are many fold. I wanted
to finish this highly acclaimed game already and know what people are talking about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>E3 and the Marketing Monster</title>
        <published>2015-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2015-06-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/e3-and-the-marketing-monster/"/>
        <id>https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/e3-and-the-marketing-monster/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;And upon us is the current E3. The marketing machine is buzzing, the internet is excited, everybody is watching the keynotes.
At the moment I only watched the Bethesda Keynote with all their glory but I am sitting ready for the Microsoft one. Why am I watching
these? Because they are lame and funny and crazy and a lot more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Player Disconnect and The Last of Us</title>
        <published>2015-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2015-04-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/player-disconnet-and-the-last-of-us/"/>
        <id>https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/player-disconnet-and-the-last-of-us/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;narfinger.github.io&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2015&#x2F;player-disconnet-and-the-last-of-us&#x2F;lastofus.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Last Of Us&quot; got wide critical acclaim from most gaming press and even most independent reviewers and analysts claim it a landmark of the current genre. Most of them mention that the ludonarrative dissonance which plagues a lot of modern games was careful avoided. The story is about a fight for survival in a world without any resources and enemies all around and the gameplay is about the same aspects. It is fast, deadly and easily ends in panic. When you sneak up on the next infected, gathering all the supplies you can find, you wonder just how you are going to get past them with only a nailbomb and 3 shotgun shells.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Tomb Raider and the Quick Event of Time</title>
        <published>2015-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2015-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/tomb-raider-and-the-quick-event-of-time/"/>
        <id>https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/tomb-raider-and-the-quick-event-of-time/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;narfinger.github.io&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2015&#x2F;tomb-raider-and-the-quick-event-of-time&#x2F;tombraider.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick time events are generally shunned in the gaming population. And even people open to different concepts hate them. I want to argue for quick time events on the example of &quot;Tomb Raider&quot; (2013).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick time events have the unique position emulating an action without a special controller required. The greatest example is probably Heavy Rain. Every movement translates to joystick movement or other controller input. And the input makes sense. If you need to brush your teeth you push the stick up and down in unison with animation. Every QTE in Heavy Rain uses movement which maps almost isomorphic to the real event happening on the screen. And because of this isomorphism our brain can see the event as a tool [1] and not just a weird input method. And if our brain sees this action as a tool we are more likely to immerse our self in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>They Bleed Pixels - The Hardcore Casual Platformer</title>
        <published>2015-04-27T01:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2015-04-27T01:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/they-bleed-pixels-the-hardcore-casual-platformer/"/>
        <id>https://narfinger.github.io/posts/2015/they-bleed-pixels-the-hardcore-casual-platformer/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;narfinger.github.io&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2015&#x2F;they-bleed-pixels-the-hardcore-casual-platformer&#x2F;theybleedpixels.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was recently playing &quot;They Bleed Pixels&quot; which at the first glance is just another 2D hardcore platformer like &quot;Super Meat Boy&quot;. However after some time I noticed that the execution is very different.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Super Meat Boy has the big problem that the length of the levels increases by a lot as you go on which can lead to a lot of frustration. One of the big reasons Super Meat Boy works and is so successful is that the reset time and repeat time is very short. Any time you die you are immediately back to the start. If you are stuck at a specific part of the level you don&#x27;t need a long time to get back to it. These two things are the major differences between old school platformers and new school. Old school fights the players while new school wants the player to succeed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</summary>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
